<demos>
  <demo file="button.py" title="Button">
    This example primarily exists to demonstrate the different alignment
    options for the FXButton class, but also demonstrates how to assign
    tooltips to FOX widgets that support them.
  </demo>
  <demo file="datatarget.py" title="Data Targets">
    This example demonstrates how to construct and use data targets
    in FOX applications.
  </demo>
  <demo file="dialog.py" title="Dialogs">
    This example demonstrates how to construct and use modal and non-modal
    dialogs in FOX applications.
  </demo>
  <demo file="dirlist.py" title="Directory List">
    This example demonstrates the FXDirList widget.
  </demo>
  <demo file="foursplit.py" title="Four-Way Splitter">
    This example demonstrates the FX4Splitter widget.
  </demo>
  <demo file="gltest.py" title="OpenGL Canvas">
    This program provides a simple example of how to use the OpenGL
    canvas widget (FXGLCanvas) but also demonstrates how to use chores and
    timers in FOX applications.
  </demo>
  <demo file="glviewer.py" title="OpenGL Viewer">
    This example is a model for a full-featured FOX application and in
    particular showcases the FXGLViewer widget. This application demonstrates
    how to set up a main window with a menu bar, toolbar and multiple
    document interface (MDI) for handling multiple OpenGL viewer windows.
  </demo>
  <demo file="groupbox.py" title="GroupBox">
    Demonstrates the FXGroupBox widget.
  </demo>
  <demo file="header.py" title="Header">
    This example demonstrates the FXHeader widget. Try turning on and off
    the "Continuous Tracking" option and then resizing the header columns to
    see the effect of this setting.
  </demo>
  <demo file="hello.py" title="Hello, World!">
    The minimalist FOX application.
  </demo>
  <demo file="hello2.py" title="Hello, World 2!">
    This "cadillac" version of "Hello, World" adds an icon and a tooltip
    to the button seen in the previous example.
  </demo>
  <demo file="iconlist.py" title="IconList">
    This example demonstrates the FXIconList widget.
  </demo>
  <demo file="imagetest.py" title="Image Test">
    Test for image widgets.
  </demo>
  <demo file="imageviewer.py" title="Image Viewer">
    This example provides the model for a full-featured image viewing and
    manipulation application, and showcases the FXImageViewer widget. Try
    out the various options under the "Manipulation" menu to see how
    you can easily transform GIF/BMP/JPEG/PNG images used in your FOX apps.
  </demo>
  <demo file="mditest.py" title="MDI Test">
    This example demonstrates the basics of setting up a multiple document
    interface (MDI) application in FOX.
  </demo>
  <demo file="neko.py" title="Neko">
    This example doesn't really introduce anything new but gave me an excuse
    to port one of my favorite Windows time-wasters to FOX.
  </demo>
  <demo file="scribble.py" title="Scribble">
    This is a nice example to demonstrate the basics of drawing into FOX
    device contexts and how to intercept mouse events. It also shows one way
    to make effective use of FOX's GUI update mechanism.
  </demo>
  <demo file="shutter.py" title="Shutter">
    Demonstrates the FXShutter widget, a Microsoft Outlook-inspired widget.
  </demo>
  <demo file="splitter.py" title="Splitter">
    Demonstrates the FXSplitter widget.
  </demo>
  <demo file="tabbook.py" title="Tabbed Book">
    Demonstrates the FXTabBook widget.
  </demo>
  <demo file="weather.py" title="Weather Report">
    Look up the local weather report anywhere in the world!
  </demo>
  <demo file="window.py" title="Periodic Table">
    This example provides a birds-eye view of many of the FOX widgets.
  </demo>
  <!--
  <demo file="textedit.py" title="Textedit">
    A simple text editor.
  </demo>
  -->
</demos>
